Zolo Stays, Near Global Village, Bangalore (K. A.)

# Priyesh Vishwakarma

DevOps/Cloud Engineer

priyeshvkarma@outlook.com https://linkedin.com/in/vkpriyesh +91-9827290794/+917987346892

### **OBJECTIVE**

About 4 years of technical expertise in implementing DevOps practices using Azure DevOps along with migration activities in different DevOps scenario. Created, deployed and managed applications on Azure and AWS stack with CI/CD implementation in agile methodology under Retail, Education & Finance domain.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Mindtree March 2021 - Present Bangalore, India

### o Role: DevOps Engineer/Scrum Master

- Automating build & release in Azure DevOps with classic editor & YAML
- Writing PowerShell to automate scheduled tasks within automation runbooks
- Release management staging, interaction with keyvault, integration of tasks, agent pool on-boarding
- Implementation of DevSecOps with Snyk & OWASP ZAP
- Handling scrum activities

**TechStar India** Bangalore, India January 2020 - February 2021

#### Client - Mindtree - Azure Resources Automation

- Role: DevOps Engineer/Scrum Master
  - Reduced operations team time by ~40% using branch strategies, ARM templates & pipelines within Azure DevOps
  - Removed dependency of external teams by automating creation of DevTest Labs & artifact management within Azure by implementing automation runbooks
  - Provided solutions to optimize cost by utilizing Azure Budget alert automation
  - Enhanced security in workloads by implementing OWASP ZAP & OWASP Dependency check
- Extensive usage and implementation of RBAC, AD and subscription for different team subsets
- Implemented Sonar Cloud integrated with Azure DevOps to provide code coverage and code analysis results
- Created build pipelines for .NET and .NET Core based application
- Created release pipeline for multi-staging environment deployment
- Monitoring alerts/issues using Application insights, Azure Monitor
- As a scrum master, managing PBIs, handling sprint activities & proper delivery of estimated tasks
- Facilitating sprint planning, scrum calls, & retrospectives using Azure DevOps

Indore, India CyberFocus August 2019 – December 2019

## **Role: Cloud Engineer/Web Developer**

- Designed & implemented cloud architecture guidelines on Azure for a multi-tenant application
- Created automation runbooks, functions & logic apps to reduce cost for customer, benefiting the users to have subscriptions at a lower cost
- Managed a team of interns as a product owner to facilitate web development through sprint planning using Azure DevOps
- Managed marketing automation using HubSpot & Trello

#### Pune/Indore, India **Tata Consultancy Services**

November 2016 – August 2019

# **Client - McGraw Hill Education (Learning Management System Integration)**

- o Role: DevOps Engineer
  - On premises application and DB migration to Azure VMs and Azure SQL
  - Managed re-architecture of legacy MVC web application to Azure services
  - Developed features in function app with C# .net core to support workflow automation
  - Developed code-base with C# on Azure services: Event Bus, Queues, Storage, Blob for persistent data access and communication across functions
  - Defined workflows in logic apps to manage frequent activities in application
  - Created CI/CD pipeline for on-prem build and deployment as well as for Azure services using ARM templates and YAML under Azure DevOps
  - Facilitating migration of tasks to Jira so as to implement robust Agile culture

- Migrated TFS code base to Azure DevOps git Repos
- Setup organisation, branching, build and release policies and triggers under Azure DevOps
- Created build pipeline under Azure DevOps pipelines using YAML for .NET MVC application and function apps
- Configured release pipeline using Azure DevOps pipelines and ARM templates to deploy, and configure resources on Azure
- Developed powershell scripts to automate service executions and job scheduling
- Analysed issues along with the root cause and provided solutions by utilising Application insights, Sumo Logic and New Relic within given SLA with RCA document creation on Confluence
- Presented major changes in CAB meetings with handling pager duty
- Worked on Enterprise Github through git CLI and Github desktop for source control management
- Facilitated scrum in Agile Methodology Jira as a Task Management tool

# • Client - Microsoft Corp. (Finance Web Application)

- Role: .NET Developer /DevOps Engineering
- Developed functionality in C# .NET 4.5 for an MVC based web application
- Created TFS policies for better utilisation of check-in/check-out/shelveset functionalities
- Managed on-prem TFS server for multi-stack application
- Created scheduling scripts for batch jobs
- Migrated TFS code base to Azure DevOps
- Migrated code base from TFS to Azure DevOps and supported in building CI/CD pipeline for .NET applications
- Automated deployment of web applications on Azure VMs using ARM templates
- Used VSTS and Git for workflow and SCM

### **LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES**

- Primary SkillSet: PowerShell, ARM Templates, Azure DevOps Build/Release, YAML, Azure Storage, Functions, Logic Apps, Runbooks, Dev Test Lab, VM, VNET
- Secondary SkillSet: SumoLogic, Terraform, .NET-C#
- Azure, Azure DevOps, Git, GitHub, Jira, Confluence, Windows, Linux Distros

### **EDUCATION**

Degree Name	Institution Name	Grades/Percentage	Year
Bachelors of Engineering in	Medicaps Institute of	6.49/10.0	2016
Computer Science and Engineering	Technology and Management, Indore (India)		
Secondary School	Advanced Academy, Indore (India)	86.8%	2012
High School	Advanced Academy, Indore (India)	9.4/10	2010

### **ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE AND ACTIVITIES**

TCS Cloud Hackathon runner-up
Diploma in Experiential Education and Practices
Telegram Support Initiative Volunteer
Microsoft Student Partner

November 2018 March 2018 April 2016 – July 2016 November 2015 – August 2016

### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth : 21st July 1995

Nationality : Indian

Interests : Photography, Volunteering, Blogging